rudolphtech.com 2019-06-28

# Legal & Privacy - Rudolph Technologies

## Privacy Policy

Rudolph Technologies, Inc. (“Rudolph Technologies”) honors the right to privacy of the visitors to its website and we are committed to safeguarding it. This policy explains how Rudolph Technologies handles any personally identifying information submitted to the company online. Personally identifying information is information that enables the company to identify the submitting individual, for example, their e-mail address, name, phone number, etc.

### How Rudolph Technologies Collects and Uses Personally Identifying Information

Any individual is free to visit the Rudolph Technologies website anonymously and is not required to reveal any personally identifying information. The sharing of an individual’s personally identifying information is fully voluntary.

The opportunity to share one’s personally identifying information has been made available on the Rudolph Technologies website to make it easier to request information or materials concerning the company’s products and services and to serve the requestor’s needs. Such personal information may include information:

  * about your computer including your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, and operating system;
  * about your visits to and use of this website including the referral source, length of visit, page views, and website navigation paths;
  * such as your email address, that you enter when you register with Rudolph Technologies website and request to be contacted; and
  * such as your name and email address, that you enter in order to set up subscriptions to Rudolph Technologies’ emails and/or newsletters.

Rudolph Technologies also collects certain anonymous information that cannot be associated with any individual personally, such as the number of visitors to the company’s website and the number of visitors requesting information. Rudolph Technologies may analyze this data to evaluate trends and statistics and to help the company assess customer needs in order to improve the website and better serve its customers.

Before you disclose to Rudolph Technologies the personal information of another person, you must obtain that person’s consent to both the disclosure and the processing of that personal information in accordance with this policy.

Personal information submitted to Rudolph Technologies through the company’s website will be used for the purposes specified in this policy or on the relevant pages of the website. Rudolph Technologies may use your personal information for the following:

  * administering Rudolph Technologies website and business;
  * personalizing Rudolph Technologies website for you;
  * enabling your use of the services available on Rudolph Technologies website;
  * sending you non-marketing commercial communications;
  * sending you email notifications that you have specifically requested;
  * sending you Rudolph Technologies email newsletter, if you have requested it (you can inform Rudolph Technologies at any time if you no longer require the newsletter); and
  * sending you marketing communications relating to our business.

Please let Rudolph Technologies know if the personal information that the company may hold about you needs to be corrected or updated.

### Disclosure and Retention of Personal Information

As reasonably necessary for the purposes set out in this policy, Rudolph Technologies may disclose your personal information to any of the company’s employees, officers, insurers, professional advisers, agents, suppliers, or subcontractors or to any Rudolph Technologies subsidiary. Further, Rudolph Technologies may disclose your personal information:

  * under certain circumstances, to the company’s business partners in order to meet the needs of the individual submitting the information;
  * to the extent that Rudolph Technologies is required to do so by law;
  * in connection with any ongoing or prospective legal proceedings;
  * in order to establish, exercise, or defend Rudolph Technologies legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk);
  * to the purchaser (or prospective purchaser) of any business or asset that Rudolph Technologies may sell; and
  * to any person who Rudolph Technologies reasonably believes may apply to a court or other competent authority for disclosure of that personal information where, in the company’s reasonable opinion, such court or authority would be reasonably likely to order disclosure of that personal information.

Other than as set forth above, Rudolph Technologies will not, without your express consent, supply your personal information to any third party whether for their or any other third party’s direct marketing or otherwise.

Information that Rudolph Technologies collects may be stored, processed in, and transferred between any of the countries in which the company operates (United States of America, Japan, China, South Korea, Taiwan, Singapore, European Union) in order to enable Rudolph Technologies to use the information in accordance with this policy. Note that such countries do not currently have data protection laws equivalent to those in force in the European Economic Area.

Personal information that you publish on the Rudolph Technologies website or submit for publication on the website may be available, via the internet, around the world. Rudolph Technologies cannot prevent the use or misuse of such information by others.

You expressly agree to the transfers of personal information described above.

Personal information that Rudolph Technologies processes for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for that purpose or those purposes. Notwithstanding the foregoing, Rudolph Technologies will retain documents (including electronic documents) containing personal data:

  * to the extent required by law;
  * if the company believes that the documents may be relevant to any ongoing or prospective legal proceedings; and
  * in order to establish, exercise, or defend the company’s legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk).

### Security of Personal Information

Rudolph Technologies will take reasonable technical and organizational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse, or alteration of your personal information. This includes the storage of all the personal information provided to the company on our secure (password- and firewall-protected) servers. Nevertheless, you hereby acknowledge that the transmission of information over the internet is inherently insecure, and Rudolph Technologies cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet.

### Accuracy and Access

Rudolph Technologies desires to maintain the accuracy of any personally identifying information an individual has provided to the company. If an individual has submitted personally identifying information to the company and it has changed, they may contact Rudolph Technologies at [info@rudolphtech.com](mailto:info@rudolphtech.com) to request a change to their personally identifying information. Similarly, an individual may request a copy of the personally identifying information stored at Rudolph Technologies by submitting such a request to the above e-mail address. Rudolph Technologies will respond to such requests within a reasonable time.

### Your Rights

You may instruct Rudolph Technologies to provide you with any personal information the company may hold about you; provision of such information will be subject to the supply of appropriate evidence of your identity. For this purpose, Rudolph Technologies will usually accept a photocopy of your passport or driver’s license certified by a notary plus an original copy of a utility bill showing your current address.

Rudolph Technologies may withhold personal information that you request to the extent permitted by law.

You may instruct Rudolph Technologies at any time not to process your personal information for marketing purposes.

In practice, you will usually either expressly agree in advance to Rudolph Technologies’ use of your personal information for marketing purposes, or the company will provide you with an opportunity to opt out of the use of your personal information for marketing purposes.

### Opting Out

You may opt out of having Rudolph Technologies maintain your personally identifying information at any time. Anyone who has submitted personally identifying information on the Rudolph Technologies website may choose not to receive additional communications from Rudolph Technologies on the company’s products, services or events that the company determines may be of further interest to the individual. If you initially choose to receive information from Rudolph Technologies but then decides you want to discontinue communications from the company, you may unsubscribe at any time by accessing the automated link provided at the bottom of the email received from Rudolph Technologies. Alternatively, you may simply send an e-mail to [info@rudolphtech.com](mailto:info@rudolphtech.com), placing the word “Unsubscribe” in the subject line and providing the details of your request.

### Cookies

Rudolph Technologies’ website uses cookies, with the exception of access to the Company's proxy materials. Cookies are small text files (a string of letters and numbers) that the Rudolph Technologies website may ask to place on the computer hard drive of an individual viewing the company’s website. If the viewer’s computer browser is set to accept cookies, then the browser can add the text in a small file. The text file is then sent back to Rudolph Technologies server each time your browser requests a page from the company’s server. Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that Rudolph Technologies may store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies. Consenting to Rudolph Technologies use of cookies in accordance with the terms of this policy when you first visit our website permits the company to use cookies every time you visit the Rudolph Technologies website.

Rudolph Technologies uses Google Analytics cookies on the company’s website to recognize a computer when a user visits the website. Rudolph Technologies will not use cookies to read other information on your computer's hard drive. Instead, the cookies may be used to confirm the access to the company website, to help Rudolph Technologies analyze and improve the usage of its website in general and potentially to personalize the website for each user. In addition, cookies could also be used if an individual submits a request with Rudolph Technologies for literature or other information. While the majority of computer browsers are initially set to accept cookies, they can be set to either refuse the placement of cookies or to provide a warning prior to the placement of a cookie - for example:

  * in Internet Explorer (version 10) you can block cookies using the cookie handling override settings available by clicking “Tools,” “Internet Options,” “Privacy,” and then “Advanced”;
  * in Firefox (version 24) you can block all cookies by clicking “Tools,” “Options,” “Privacy,” selecting “Use custom settings for history” from the drop-down menu, and unticking “Accept cookies from sites”; and
  * in Chrome (version 29), you can block all cookies by accessing the “Customize and control” menu, and clicking “Settings,” “Show advanced settings,” and “Content settings,” and then selecting “Block sites from setting any data” under the “Cookies” heading.

Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites. If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on Rudolph Technologies website. Cookies already stored on your computer may be deleted from the computer but as with blocking cookies, deletion of cookies may have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.

### Children under the age of 13

The Rudolph Technologies website does not target and is not intended for children under the age of 13. Rudolph Technologies acknowledges and follows the requirements of the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). To that end, Rudolph Technologies’ website does not target children or knowingly collect data from them. If Rudolph Technologies becomes aware that a child’s personal data has been submitted to the company, such data will be removed from the company’s system.

### Amendments

Rudolph Technologies may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on the company’s website. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you understand any changes to this policy. Rudolph Technologies may notify you of changes to this policy by email.

### Contact Rudolph Technologies

If there are any questions about Rudolph Technologies’ privacy policy, please feel free to e-mail the company at [info@ruolphtech.com](mailto:info@ruolphtech.com) with the inquiry.

Policy last revised on May 24, 2018  

## Terms of Use

Thank you for visiting Rudolph Technologies' website, with a homepage located at [www.rudolphtech.com](http://www.rudolphtech.com/) (the "Site"). This Site is operated by Rudolph Technologies, Inc. ("Rudolph Technologies"). These Terms of Use describe the rules that apply when you visit the Site. We may change these Terms of Use at any time, and by using this Site you agree to any and all such changes.

Rudolph Technologies may change the products and/or services offered on this Site at any time. You understand that Rudolph Technologies may discontinue or restrict any visitor's use of this Site for any reason or no reason without notice.

The materials on this Site belong to Rudolph Technologies and are protected by United States and foreign trademark and copyright laws. There are some important restrictions about copying these materials. If you use the materials in a way that is not clearly allowed by these Terms of Use, you are violating your contract with us and may be violating copyright, trademark, and other laws. In that case, we automatically revoke your permission to use the materials and you must immediately destroy any copies you have made. While you comply with these Terms of Use, you may download or print one copy of the materials on this Site, but only for your personal, noncommercial use. When you download or print a copy of the materials on this Site, you must also include all copyright and other notices that are in the materials, including the copyright notice on the bottom of the page. Title to the materials remains with us or with the authors of the materials contained on this Site. All rights not expressly granted are reserved.

This Site may contain links to websites or networks operated by other parties, or display information or materials regarding products or services offered by other entities. These other sites and other parties are not under the control of Rudolph Technologies, and Rudolph Technologies is not responsible for the content available on any other internet sites linked to or from the Site or any action or inaction of any third parties. Rudolph Technologies does not endorse or warrant the goods or services of any third party. You may visit other linked sites or engage in business with any third party at your own risk.

While Rudolph Technologies is pleased to receive feedback and comments from visitors to this Site, we want you to understand that any information that you submit through this Site in any form will be considered non-personal, non-confidential, and non-proprietary. If you transmit any ideas, information, concepts, know-how or techniques or materials to us through this Site, you hereby grant Rudolph Technologies an unrestricted, royalty-free, irrevocable license to use, reproduce, display, perform, modify, transmit and distribute them, and agree that Rudolph Technologies is free to use them for any purpose. Note that your e-mail submissions over a public network such as the internet may not be secure. Please consider this fact before e-mailing to or electronically submitting to Rudolph Technologies any information. 

All content on this site is provided to you on an "as is" "as available" basis without warranty of any kind, either express or implied, including but not limited to the implied warranties of merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, and non-infringement. Rudolph Technologies makes no warranty as to the accuracy, completeness, currency, or reliability of any content available through this website. You are responsible for verifying any information before relying on it. Use of the website and the content available on the website is at your sole risk.

Rudolph Technologies makes no representations or warranties that use of the website will be uninterrupted or error-free. You are responsible for taking all necessary precautions to ensure that any content you may obtain from the website is free of viruses.

Rudolph Technologies specifically disclaims any liability, whether based in contract, tort, strict liability or otherwise, for any direct, indirect, incidental, consequential, or special damages arising out of or in any way connected with access to or use of the website, even if Rudolph Technologies has been advised of the possibility of such damages, including but not limited to reliance by any party on any content obtained through the use of the website, or that arises in connection with mistakes or omissions in, or delays in transmission of, information to or from the user, interruptions in telecommunications connections to the website or viruses, whether caused in whole or in part by negligence, acts of god, telecommunications failure, theft or destruction of, or unauthorized access to the website, or related information or programs.

By using this Site, you agree that the only proper jurisdiction and venue for any dispute with Rudolph Technologies, or in any way relating to your use of this Site, is in the state and federal courts in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, U.S.A. You further agree and consent to the exercise of personal jurisdiction in these courts in connection with any dispute involving Rudolph Technologies or its affiliates, employees, officers, directors, agents, and providers. Any claims relating to the information, services or products available on this Site will be governed by the laws of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, except those pertaining to choice of law.

If any provisions of these Terms of Use are held to be invalid or unenforceable, such provision shall be struck and the remaining provisions shall be enforced. Rudolph Technologies' failure to act with respect to any failure by you or others to comply with these Terms of Use does not waive Rudolph Technologies' right to act with respect to subsequent or similar failures. These Terms of Use set forth the entire understanding and agreement between us with respect to the subject matter hereof. Notwithstanding the foregoing, if you desire to use certain additional services available on the Site, supplemental terms and conditions may apply.

S3000, S2000, StepFAST, F30, Firefly, Dragonfly, Clearfind, Truebump, Equipment Sentinel, EASy and AWX are trademarks of Rudolph Technologies, Inc.

MetaPULSE, NSX, JetStep, Discover, ControlWORKS, RecipeWORKS, TrueADC, AutoShell, YieldMine and PrecisionWoRx are registered trademarks of Rudolph Technologies, Inc.

PatMAX is a registered trademark of Cognex Corporation.

Thanks again for visiting the Site. We hope you found it interesting and informative. We would appreciate your feedback regarding the Site, so if you have questions or comments, please contact us at [info@rudolphtech.com](mailto:info@rudolphtech.com).
